androidsage.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy

## We respect the privacy of our visitors at AndroidSage.

By using our website (AndroidSage), you are consenting to comply with out Privacy Policies.

## Who we are?

Our website address is: https://www.androidsage.com. We are technology experts and we provide solutions through our helpful how-to tutorials, and news, downloads, and much more.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Sign Up or Login

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**  
When Logging in, signing up, subscribing, or registering on our site (as appropriate) you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?  **We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, comments or enter information on our site.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Google Adsense and Analytics

We are in compliant with GDPR Privacy Policy rules updated by Google and their products [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). By accepting our Consent Cookie, you are complying to show both Personalized and Non-Personalized ads from Google Adsense, and their AdWords advertising partners.

### OneSignal and SuperPWA

In order to serve you best, OneSignal stores IP address and the device ID you are using for sending notifications when new posts are published. But that is only if you opt-in for using these services. You can simply opt-out by visiting any page and unchecking the OneSignal icon on the bottom right corner. For PWA, we do not collect or store any device information. You can add our Progressive App any time.

### Contact forms

When you submit a support question we collect your first name, and/or last name (only when provided) and your email address so that we can correspond with you.  
When you subscribe to our newsletter we collect your name (only when provided) and your emailaddress so that we can correspond with you. Your personal data will not only be stored in the website’s database but also in Wordpress, the application we use to send our newsletters.  
When you submit a request for a new add-on we store your emailaddress so that we can keep you updated about your request.

Emails will also be sent through Jetpack by WordPress where it will be stored for 45 days.  
You can view, update, download or delete your personal data by simply unsubscribing from our email list.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track visitors on this site.  
Google Analytics uses cookies to collect this data.  
In order to be compliant with the new regulation Google included a [data processing amendment](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/dpa/dataprocessingamendment_20130906.html).  
The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled.  
We don’t use other Google services in combination with Google Analytics cookies.

### Email subscription: Jetpack by WordPress

We use **Jetpack by WordPress  **for our newsletter campaigns.  
Jetpack email subscription is the default marketing automation platform and is GDPR compliant. They have an automated campaign builder that makes it easy to send emails when a post is bublished.

### What third parties we receive data from?

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We, therefore, have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## Who we share your data with

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data?

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data?

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### How we protect your data?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise, transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.  
However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### What data breach procedures we have in place?

**We can delete your data when asked.**

**According** **  to GDPR:**

  * Transparency: We added additional information about how, and when, we collect, use and share your personal information.
  * GDPR: Entering into effect on May 25, 2018, GDPR enforces a new set of rules and standards for the processing of personal data of individuals in the EU. Payoneer is compliant with GDPR and our updated Privacy & Cookies Policy takes into account and applies the requirements of the regulation.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act  
**CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our homepage, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.  
Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:  
• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Users are able to change their personal information:  
• By logging into their account  
How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)  
**When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices  
**The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include having played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.  
In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
We will notify the users via email  
• Within 7 business days  
We will notify the users via in-site notification  
• Within 7 business days  
We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

## Our contact information

Contact us by visiting our [Contact us](https://www.androidsage.com/contact-us/) page or to know more about us, visit our website’s [About us](https://www.androidsage.com/about-us/) page.
